<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on Cliffe Group</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on Cliffe Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matt Cliffe</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/mattcliffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/mattcliffe/</guid>
      <description>matthew.cliffe[at]nottingham.ac.uk Matt is an Associate Professor at the University of Nottingham.&#xA;He received his DPhil (2015) at the University of Oxford under the supervision of Prof. Andrew Goodwin on the characterization of disordered framework materials. He then took up a Research Fellowship at Sidney Sussex College at the University of Cambridge, where he worked with Prof. Clare Grey in the Department of Chemistry, before moving to the University of Nottingham in 2018 as the inaugural Hobday Fellow, being promoted to Assistant Professor in 2021 and Associate Professor in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rinku Kushwaha</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/rinkukushwaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/rinkukushwaha/</guid>
      <description>rinku.kushwaha[at]nottingham.ac.uk Rinku joined the Cliffe group as a Postdoctoral Research Associate (PDRA). His research explores the magnetic and conducting properties resulting from doping in metal–organic frameworks (MOF). He comes from Uttar Pradesh, India. Rinku obtained his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree from the University of Allahabad and later joined the Indian Institute of Science Education and Research (IISER), Pune, for an integrated MS-PhD program. He completed his Ph.D. in Chemistry under the supervision of Prof.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joseph Ogar</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/josephogar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/josephogar/</guid>
      <description>Joseph.Ogar[at]nottingham.ac.uk Dr Joseph Ogar began his academic career in 2013 as a member of the Department of Chemistry at the University of Calabar, following his graduation from the University of Nigeria, Nsukka, in 2010. He earned his Master’s degree in Inorganic Chemistry from the University of Calabar in 2016.&#xA;In 2017, Dr Ogar joined the research group of Professor Neil Champness at the University of Nottingham, where he completed his PhD in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luis León Alcaide</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/luisleonalcaide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/luisleonalcaide/</guid>
      <description>Luis.Alcaide[at]nottingham.ac.uk Luis León joined the Cliffe Group as a Postdoctoral Research Associate, where he investigates highly frustrated MOF networks to explore novel magnetic behaviors. He completed his PhD in Nanoscience and Nanotechnology in 2024 at ICMOL, University of Valencia, Spain, under the supervision of Professor Mínguez Espallargas. Outside of his academic work, Luis enjoys food—especially when paired with a good wine—and is an avid basketball fan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andy Jones</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/andyjones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/andyjones/</guid>
      <description>andrew.jones1[at]nottingham.ac.uk Andy is a PhD student in the CDT in Sustainable Chemistry, with a background in a Green Chemistry from the University of York. His research focuses on creating single atom catalysts on MOF supports, using defect sites to stabilise the catalyst atoms.&#xA;Outside of Chemistry, he is a keen chef, enjoys Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu and is a big fan of MMA</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simrun Lata</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/simrunlata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/simrunlata/</guid>
      <description>pcxsp10[at]@exmail.nottingham.ac.uk Simrun is a PhD student working in the School of Chemistry and Sir Peter Mansfield Imaging Centre with Dr Walter Köckenburger. Their research focusses on studying solid-state DNP-MAS NMR enhancement in metal-organic frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoxuan Su , 苏晓轩</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/xiaoxuansu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/xiaoxuansu/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxuan.Su[at]nottingham.ac.uk Xiaoxuan earned his Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Chemistry from the University of Sheffield in 2021, returned to China and worked as a research assistant for two years before deciding to pursue his Ph.D joint between the Pilgrim and Cliffe Groups. During his spare time, he enjoys reading and playing board games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amos Blyth</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/amosblyth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/amosblyth/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxuan.Su[at]nottingham.ac.uk Amos completed his master’s research with the Cliffe group in 2023 and returned in 2024 to undertake a PhD in quantum radical metal organic frameworks. His work focuses on investigating the local structure of two- and three-dimensional frameworks using X-ray and electron pair distribution function (PDF) analysis.&#xA;Amos loves to bird watch and sends much of his free time doing this. Else, he’ll be out running, sitting with a coffee in his rocking chair reading or crocheting, or playing video games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kuba Lemanski</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/kubalemanski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/kubalemanski/</guid>
      <description>Kuba.Lemanski[at]nottingham.ac.uk Kuba is a PhD student working on the DISCO-MOF project with a background in inorganic chemistry. His research focuses on the preparation of radical ligand MOFs with early transition metals and investigating their properties. Outside of chemistry he loves spending time in nature, hiking, cycling and especially running. Some of his other interests include cooking, travelling and gaming as well as trying as many types of tea as possible (current favourite being apple strudel).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alumni</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/alumni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/CliffeGroupWebsite/people/alumni/</guid>
      <description>2020-23, 2018-19 Madeleine Geers (PhD, MSci), PDRA, Clulow Group, Uppsala University&#xA;2019-23 Jem Pitcairn (PhD, PDRA), PDRA, Clark Group, University of Birmingham&#xA;2020-21 Claire Housely (PhD), Senior Nuclear Policy Advisor, Dept. for Energy Security and Net Zero, @StringaTheory&#xA;2016-21 Francesca Firth (MSci, PhD), Veranova, @FC_Firth&#xA;2023-24 Amelia Thompson (MSci)&#xA;2023-24 Eda Bonde Colliver (MSci)&#xA;2022-23 Emily Myatt (MSci)&#xA;2021-22 Jacob Brownlee (MSci)&#xA;2021-22 Sophie McMillan (MSci)&#xA;2021-22 Joel Shenton (MSci)</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
