<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on Cliffe Group</title>
    <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on Cliffe Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matt Cliffe</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/mattcliffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/mattcliffe/</guid>
      <description>matthew.cliffe[at]nottingham.ac.uk Matt is an Associate Professor at the University of Nottingham.
He received his DPhil (2015) at the University of Oxford under the supervision of Prof. Andrew Goodwin on the characterization of disordered framework materials. He then took up a Research Fellowship at Sidney Sussex College at the University of Cambridge, where he worked with Prof. Clare Grey in the Department of Chemistry, before moving to the University of Nottingham in 2018 as the inaugural Hobday Fellow, being promoted to Assistant Professor in 2021 and Associate Professor in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jem Pitcairn</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/jempitcairn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/jempitcairn/</guid>
      <description>jem.pitcairn[at]nottingham.ac.uk Jem is a PhD student investigating low-dimensional metal-organic magnets, with a particular focus on air-sensitive synthesis and neutron scattering studies of linker bridged metal-chloride chains. He joined the Cliffe group in October 2019 having previously worked as a research associate in the Materials for Applied Surface Science team at Illumina. Jem graduated from the University of Sheffield with an MEng in Materials Science in 2017. For his Masters&amp;rsquo; project he studied the stress control of magnetic domain motion in ferromagnetic nano-wires with Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maddie Geers</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/maddiegeers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/maddiegeers/</guid>
      <description>pcymrge[at]nottingham.ac.uk Maddie re-joined the Cliffe group as a PhD student in October 2020, after doing a MSci project (18-19). Her studies concentrate on the magnetic properties of metal thiocyanate frameworks and how they can be controlled through doping the structures with alternative metals. She has a focus on neutron diffraction measurements, so she is based at the Institut Laue-Langevin neutron research centre, where she is co-supervised by Dr Laura Cañadillas-Delgado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Jones</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/andyjones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/andyjones/</guid>
      <description>andrew.jones1[at]nottingham.ac.uk Andy is a PhD student in the CDT in Sustainable Chemistry, with a background in a Green Chemistry from the University of York. His research focuses on creating single atom catalysts on MOF supports, using defect sites to stabilise the catalyst atoms.
Outside of Chemistry, he is a keen chef, enjoys Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu and is a big fan of MMA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simrun Lal</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/simrunlal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/simrunlal/</guid>
      <description>pcxsp10[at]@exmail.nottingham.ac.uk Simrun is a PhD student working in the School of Chemistry and Sir Peter Mansfield Imaging Centre with Dr Walter Köckenburger. Their research focusses on studying solid-state DNP-MAS NMR enhancement in metal-organic frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoxuan Su</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/xiaoxuansu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/xiaoxuansu/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxuan.Su[at]nottingham.ac.uk Xiaoxuan earned his Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Chemistry from the University of Sheffield in 2021, returned to China and worked as a research assistant for two years before deciding to pursue his Ph.D joint between the Pilgrim and Cliffe Groups. During his spare time, he enjoys reading and playing board games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eda Bonde Colliver</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/edabondecolliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/edabondecolliver/</guid>
      <description>pcyec8[at]nottingham.ac.uk Eda is a fourth-year MSci student researching ruthenium MOFs. Outside of chemistry, she is a keen water polo player and rower, and enjoys film photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amelia Thompson</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/ameliathompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/ameliathompson/</guid>
      <description>pcyat14[at]nottingham.ac.uk Amelia is a fourth year Chemistry and Molecular Physics student looking into orbital liquid behaviour in nitrite perovskites. Amelia figure skates and used to compete when she was younger. She is also a part of the archery team at UoN archery club and enjoys reading in her spare time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumni</title>
      <link>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/alumni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//cliffe.nottingham.ac.uk/people/alumni/</guid>
      <description>2020-21 Claire Housely (PhD), Committee Specialist for the House of Commons Science and Technology Committee, @StringaTheory
2016-21 Francesca Firth (MSci, PhD), Veranova, @FC_Firth
2022-23 Emily Myatt (MSci)
2022-23 Jo Blyth (MSci)
2021-22 Jacob Brownlee (MSci)
2021-22 Sophie McMillan (MSci)
2021-22 Joel Shenton (MSci)
2020-21 Alex Ollier de Marichard (MRes)
2020-21 Sara Incarbone (MSci)
2020-21 Adam Lansdowne (MSci)
2020-21 Peter Speakman (MSci)
2019-20 Chris Rink (MSci)
2019-20 Callum Rosenberg (MSci), Champness Group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
